<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<query columns="21" rows="936"><row><criteria_txt>(iv)(v)</criteria_txt><danger></danger><date_inscribed>2011</date_inscribed><historical_description></historical_description><http_url>http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1363</http_url><id_number>1363</id_number><image_url>http://whc.unesco.org/uploads/sites/site_1363.jpg</image_url><iso_code>at,fr,de,it,si,ch</iso_code><justification></justification><latitude>47.2783333333</latitude><location></location><longitude>8.2075000000</longitude><long_description></long_description><region>Europe and North America</region><revision_extension></revision_extension><secondary_dates></secondary_dates><short_description>&lt;p&gt;This serial property of 111 small individual sites encompasses the remains of prehistoric pile-dwelling (or stilt house) settlements in and around the Alps built from around 5000 to 500 B.C. on the edges of lakes, rivers or wetlands. Excavations, only conducted in some of the sites, have yielded evidence that provides insight into life in prehistoric times during the Neolithic and Bronze Age in Alpine Europe and the way communities interacted with their environment. Fifty-six of the sites are located in Switzerland. The settlements are a unique group of exceptionally well-preserved and culturally rich archaeological sites, which constitute one of the most important sources for the study of early agrarian societies in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</short_description><site>Prehistoric Pile dwellings around the Alps</site><states>Austria,France,Germany,Italy,Slovenia,Switzerland</states><transboundary>1</transboundary><unique_number>1782</unique_number></row><row><criteria_txt>(iv)</criteria_txt><danger></danger><date_inscribed>1983</date_inscribed><historical_description></historical_description><http_url>http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/275</http_url><id_number>275</id_number><image_url>http://whc.unesco.org/uploads/sites/site_275.jpg</image_url><iso_code>br,ar</iso_code><justification></justification><latitude>-28.5433333300</latitude><location>State of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; Province of Misiones, Argentina</location><longitude>-54.2658333300</longitude><long_description>&lt;p&gt;The remains of these Jesuit missions are outstanding examples of a type of building and of an architectural ensemble which illustrate a significant period of the history of Argentina and Brazil. The ruins of Sa&amp;otilde; Miguel das Miss&amp;otilde;es in Brazil and those of San Ignacio Min&amp;iacute;, Santa Ana, Nuestra Se&amp;ntilde;ora de Loreto and Santa Mar&amp;iacute;a la Mayor in Argentina lie in the heart of a tropical forest. They are impressive remains of five Jesuit missions, built in the land of the Guaranis during the 17th and 18th centuries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;All these Guarani &lt;em&gt;reducciones&lt;/em&gt; (settlements) are laid out on the same model: the church, the residence of the Fathers, and the regularly spaced houses of the Indians are laid out around a large square. However, each of the &lt;em&gt;reducciones&lt;/em&gt; is characterized by a specific layout and a different state of conservation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;San Ignacio Min&amp;iacute;, founded in 1611, was moved on two successive occasions, settling in its present site in 1696. It incorporates important monumental remains: churches, residence of the Fathers, schools. The ruins are accessible and in a relatively good state of preservation. It is the most eminent example of a &lt;em&gt;reduccion&lt;/em&gt; preserved on Argentinean territory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Ana, founded in 1633 on the Sierra del Tape, was removed in 1638 to the bank of the Paran&amp;aacute; river and once more to its present site, 45&amp;nbsp;km from Posadas. The ruins of the church, which are accessible by a monumental stairway, emerge from a forest site. It resisted pillage following the expulsion of the Jesuits in 1767.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Nuestra Se&amp;ntilde;ora de Loreto, founded in 1610, was moved in 1631 to its present site 53&amp;nbsp;km from Posadas. The mission included a printing-press. The church and the Fathers' house were built by Brother Bressanelli, as at San Ignacio Min&amp;iacute;. The ruins of the Indian village have been partially cleared of vegetation&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Mar&amp;iacute;a la Mayor, founded in 1626, was moved to its present site in 1633. Not far from the ruins of the church, important remains of the residence of the fathers are still standing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Sa&amp;otilde; Miguel, founded on the site of the Itaiaceco in 1632, was transferred first to Concepci&amp;oacute;n, and then in 1687 to its present site on the banks of the Piratini. Of the village not one building remains intact; all that are visible are the foundations of the Fathers' residence, the school, and the walls of the cemetery, along with some vestiges of Indian habitations. In a site that is periodically invaded by vegetation are found the ruins of the church attributed to Father Gian Battista Primoli, a Jesuit architect of Milanese origins, well known for his work in Buenos Aires, C&amp;oacute;rdoba and Concepci&amp;oacute;n. This Baroque church, finished in 1750, was ravaged 10 years by fire. It was restored in a rather summary manner during the years which preceded the definitive expulsion of the Jesuits in 1768.&lt;/p&gt;</long_description><region>Latin America and the Caribbean</region><revision_extension>bis</revision_extension><secondary_dates>1984</secondary_dates><short_description>&lt;p&gt;The ruins of S&amp;atilde;o Miguel das Miss&amp;otilde;es in Brazil, and those of San Ignacio Min&amp;iacute;, Santa Ana, Nuestra Se&amp;ntilde;ora de Loreto and Santa Mar&amp;iacute;a la Mayor in Argentina, lie at the heart of a tropical forest. They are the impressive remains of five Jesuit missions, built in the land of the Guaranis during the 17th and 18th centuries. Each is characterized by a specific layout and a different state of conservation.&lt;/p&gt;</short_description><site>Jesuit Missions of the Guaranis: San Ignacio Mini, Santa Ana, Nuestra Señora de Loreto and Santa Maria Mayor (Argentina), Ruins of Sao Miguel das Missoes (Brazil)</site><states>Brazil,Argentina</states><transboundary>1</transboundary><unique_number>326</unique_number></row><row><criteria_txt>(vii)(viii)(ix)(x)</criteria_txt><danger></danger><date_inscribed>1979</date_inscribed><historical_description>&lt;p&gt;Established September 1993, under the provisions of the Park Act.&lt;/p&gt;</historical_description><http_url>http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/72</http_url><id_number>72</id_number><image_url>http://whc.unesco.org/uploads/sites/site_72.jpg</image_url><iso_code>ca,us</iso_code><justification></justification><latitude>61.1975833300</latitude><location>Kluane: Yukon Territory (Canada) and Alaska (USA)&#xd;
&#xd;
Glacier Bay:  Alaska (USA)&#xd;
&#xd;
Tatshenshini:  Province of British Columbia (Canada)</location><longitude>-140.9919722000</longitude><long_description>&lt;p&gt;A unique area with high mountain peaks, foothills, glacial systems, lakes, streams, valleys and coastal landscapes. The Wrangell-St Elias region represents the most extensive array of glaciers and ice fields outside the polar region. These features and the high mountains of the Wrangell-St Elias, Chugach and Kluane ranges have resulted in the region becoming known as the 'Mountain Kingdom' of North America. Geologically the mountains are included in the Pacific mountain system and include the 130&amp;nbsp;km long Bagley ice field, the second-highest peak in the USA (Mount St Elias) and the largest piedmont glacier on the North American continent (Malaspina Glacier). Extensive lowlands are found only in the centre and along north-western fringes of the region. Elsewhere lowlands are sandwiched between mountains and sea or occur as narrow valleys and plateaux grading into upland and serrated peaks. Principal drainages include the Copper, Chitina, White, Alsek and Donjek rivers and tributaries. The Malaspina foreland coastal area comprises mainly long, straight piedmont glacial beaches cut through by numerous often sizeable glacial-melt drainage-ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The wide ranges of climatic zones and elevations in the region have resulted in a great variety of ecosystems representing three major biomes or broad vegetational subdivisions: the coastal coniferous biome; the northern coniferous biome; and the alpine tundra biome. The coastal coniferous biome includes coastal spruce-hemlock forests, tall shrub thickets and bogs and marshes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The northern coniferous biome includes closed tall spruce and deciduous forests, open, low mixed evergreen and deciduous forests, tall shrub thickets and low shrub thickets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The alpine tundra biome includes moist sedge and grass alpine tundra and dry alpine tundra: moist sedge and grass alpine tundra at 900-1,500&amp;nbsp;m on gradual slopes, meadow-like tundra composed of sedges and grasses interspersed with low shrubs such as blueberry and Labrador tea; and dry alpine tundra, on steeper mountain slopes and exposed ridges from 900&amp;nbsp;m to the elevation of perpetual ice and snow comprising low, matted alpine plants dominated by mountain avens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;There is a great variety of fauna reflecting the habitat diversity. Carnivores include coyote, grey wolf, red fox, short-tailed weasel, mink, wolverine, river otter, lynx and the more easily visible brown bear and black bear. A rare bluish colour phase of the black bear, known locally as the glacier bear, is centred in the vicinity of Yakutat. Other mammals include pica and snowshoe hare, arctic ground squirrel, beaver Castor, muskrat and porcupine. Rodents include the hoary marmot. Moose and caribou range in lower elevations and mountain goat and Dally sheep occupy high mountainous areas. Bison were introduced in 1950 and again in 1962. Black-tailed deer may occur along coastal fringes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The avifauna includes spruce grouse, ruffed grouse, willow ptarmigan, rock ptarmigan, white-tailed ptarmigan, trumpeter swan and many song birds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;All five species of Alaskan Pacific salmon including red salmon, chum, silver salmon, pink salmon and king salmon spawn in park or preserve waters. Freshwater fish species include Dolly Virden, lake trout, steelhead, cutthroat trout, arctic grayling, turbot, round whitefish and humpback whitefish.&lt;/p&gt;</long_description><region>Europe and North America</region><revision_extension>ter</revision_extension><secondary_dates>1992, 1994</secondary_dates><short_description>&lt;p&gt;These parks comprise an impressive complex of glaciers and high peaks on both sides of the border between Canada (Yukon Territory and British Columbia) and the United States (Alaska). The spectacular natural landscapes are home to many grizzly bears, caribou and Dall's sheep. The site contains the largest non-polar icefield in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</short_description><site>Kluane / Wrangell-St Elias / Glacier Bay / Tatshenshini-Alsek</site><states>Canada,United States of America</states><transboundary>1</transboundary><unique_number>78</unique_number></row><row><criteria_txt>(viii)</criteria_txt><danger></danger><date_inscribed>2000</date_inscribed><historical_description></historical_description><http_url>http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/898</http_url><id_number>898</id_number><image_url>http://whc.unesco.org/uploads/sites/site_898.jpg</image_url><iso_code>fi,se</iso_code><justification></justification><latitude>63.3000000000</latitude><location></location><longitude>21.3000000000</longitude><long_description>&lt;p&gt;The site lies within the specific area known as the 'High Coast' of Sweden, and is located on the west shore of the southern Gulf of Bothnia, a northern extension of the Baltic Sea. The High Coast is a mosaic of human and natural landscapes with agriculture, fishing and tourism as the main economic activities. It has a long history of human use dating from late Stone Age dwellings and remains of an Iron Age village.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Physically, the archipelago has irregular topography with a series of lakes, inlets and flat hills rising to 350&amp;nbsp;m. Vegetation is typical of the west Eurasian taiga with a mix of alpine, boreal forest and wetland communities. It displays marked altitudinal zonation and great spatial variability, with high floristic diversity, due to the complex pattern of soils and substrate on an uplifted, high-relief land surface. The offshore islets support small seabird populations. The main natural values of the High Coast are geological and relate to the glacial history of the area. Since the retreat of the last ice cap, 18,000-9600 BP, the land began to uplift. The geomorphology of the region is largely shaped by the combined processes of glaciation, glacial retreat and the emergence of new land from the sea which continues today at a rate of 0.9&amp;nbsp;m per century. In conclusion, the High Coast is one of many places in the world that is experiencing uplift as a result of deglaciation. Isostatic rebound is well illustrated and the distinctiveness of the site is the extent of the total isostatic uplift which, at 294&amp;nbsp;m, exceeds others. The geological, topographical and climatic conditions also combine to make the High Coast a distinctive vegetation boundary zone, with a rare blend of southern plants with northern boreal, western oceanic and eastern continental species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The High Coast contains large mammal species, such as bear, lynx and moose, which are widespread in Scandinavia. Whereas the coastal birdlife is typical of the region, the terrestrial birdlife is rich and varied due to the altitudinal range and topographic diversity which also provide habitats attractive to some rare birds of southern origin. Invertebrate fauna is not well known, although insects may be richer than elsewhere because of the floristic diversity. The biological character of the marine environment is a consequence of several major controlling influences such as: brackish waters of very low salinity; the most sharply contoured submarine topography in the Baltic, extending to depths in excess of 200&amp;nbsp;m close inshore; little tidal influence, with shifting water levels determined mainly by changing weather conditions of air pressure and wind; and seasonal ice cover. The resultant mosaic of shallow, sheltered embayment and deep, open waters provides a range of habitats for a mix of marine, brackish and freshwater species, low in species diversity but high in population numbers for some macrofauna species.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The special feature of the marine realm, imparting the greatest scientific significance, represents the submarine extension of the topographical continuum of landscapes undergoing isostatic uplift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Continual elevation of the land results in inlets becoming progressively cut off from the sea, transforming them into estuaries and ultimately lakes. The terrestrial influence progressively extends seawards into the Bothnian Sea. This process has major effects for the associated plants and animals that must constantly adapt to the changing environments. The whole creates a landscape of great scenic value and aesthetic appeal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Archaeological sites, some remarkably well preserved, reveal 7,000 years of human agrarian and maritime settlement in the High Coast, all confined by the steep topography into a narrow coastal strip of 2-3&amp;nbsp;km. Displacement of coastal settlements by isostatic land uplift has created a relict cultural landscape with evidence of different peoples at successive levels above the sea. The oldest remains, from the Stone Age of 5000 BC, now stand at 150&amp;nbsp;m above sea level, and corresponding Bronze Age and Iron Age are found, respectively, at 30&amp;nbsp;m and 15&amp;nbsp;m above the present shoreline. Adaptation of peoples to conditions created by land uplift means the geological history and cultural history are, thus, closely entwined.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The remarkable imprint of 7,000 years of human occupancy on a landscape experiencing the world's highest isostatic uplift is a significant cultural heritage asset, and one that is important to preserve for future generations. However, cultural landscapes and prehistoric remains are widespread throughout Scandinavia.&lt;/p&gt;</long_description><region>Europe and North America</region><revision_extension>Bis</revision_extension><secondary_dates>2006</secondary_dates><short_description>&lt;p&gt;The Kvarken Archipelago (Finland) and the High Coast (Sweden) are situated in the Gulf of Bothnia, a northern extension of the Baltic Sea. The 5,600 islands of the Kvarken Archipelago feature unusual ridged washboard moraines, &amp;lsquo;De Geer moraines&amp;rsquo;, formed by the melting of the continental ice sheet, 10,000 to 24,000 years ago. The Archipelago is continuously rising from the sea in a process of rapid glacio-isostatic uplift, whereby the land, previously weighed down under the weight of a glacier, lifts at rates that are among the highest in the world. As a consequence islands appear and unite, peninsulas expand, and lakes evolve from bays and develop into marshes and peat fens. The High Coast has also been largely shaped by the combined processes of glaciation, glacial retreat and the emergence of new land from the sea. Since the last retreat of the ice from the High Coast 9,600 years ago, the uplift has been in the order of 285 m which is the highest known ''rebound''. The site affords outstanding opportunities for the understanding of the important processes that formed the glaciated and land uplift areas of the Earth''s surface.&lt;/p&gt;</short_description><site>High Coast / Kvarken Archipelago</site><states>Finland,Sweden</states><transboundary>1</transboundary><unique_number>1050</unique_number></row><row><criteria_txt>(ii)(iv)</criteria_txt><danger></danger><date_inscribed>1999</date_inscribed><historical_description>&lt;p&gt;The definition of the term "belfry" was somewhat vague at the outset. Referring originally to the mobile wooden towers used in siege warfare, the term is later applied by Viollet-le-Duc in the Dictionnaire raisonn&amp;eacute; de l'architecture fran&amp;ccedil;aise to the wooden watchtowers mounted on the palisades surrounding the portus or preurban centres. It was to be applied occasionally to towers of all sorts, but particularly to those housing bells or standing next to the bell-tower.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Palisades, bells, and the right to possess bells are all closely associated with the development of urban life which took place in these regions following the Viking raids of the 9th century. A favourable geographic situation at the heart of Europe, the re-establishment of major trade routes such as Bruges/Brugge-Cologne, and the improvement of navigable waterways at regional and national level made this region the ideal site for contact, trade, and the meeting of cultures. Travelling merchants re-appeared and perhaps began to organize and establish permanent warehouses near the castra of the feudal lords. These pre-urban groupings, which often grew up along river valleys, are the origin of towns like Tournai and Gent, along the Escaut. Locations where roads met navigable waterways were particularly propitious for the organization of markets, first temporary but later becoming permanent fairs, encouraging merchants to settle in one spot. In addition, the cloth-weaving industry seems to have developed from the 11th century onwards, in small centres such as Lille, Ypres (Ieper), Bruges (Brugge), Ghent (Gent), etc. Trade and cloth-weaving became key factors for the development of the pre-urban centre, which began to make its presence felt as an organized body through the influence of the professional bodies (guilds, corporations) and to mark out its physical bounds by building ramparts or palisades with belfries to provide safety against marauders. From the 12th century onwards, such ramparts were often rebuilt in stone and subsequently extended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Such centres expanded under the protection provided - for a fee - by the castra, whose importance and role gradually diminished to such an extent that in some cases, such as Ghent and Antwerp (Antwerpen), the abandoned castles were taken over by the local burghers. This development illustrates the insoluble conflicts between ch&amp;acirc;telain and burghers keen to organize as a "commune" with their own administration. Again from the 12th century onwards, successive Counts of Flanders favoured the burghers which led to the flowering, from Arras to Bruges, of thriving towns demanding written proof of their rights and privileges in the form of charters. These charters, issued from the 12th century onwards, are extremely diverse and fragmentary, and extremely practical in nature, often in the form of a step by step approach setting a legal seal on gradually acquired rights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The commune was in fact made up of all the burghers living in the city who had given their oath of allegiance. At their head were the elected magistrates, the aldermen or scabini responsible for carrying out administrative functions, and the mayeur, who had no specific powers. The chief alderman held an important position, since he presided over the court and council meetings, kept the seals of the town and the keys to its gates, and commanded the town militia which owed the ban (feudal service) to the overlord. As feudal lord, the commune had other obligations to the seigneur, such as the payment of aid in the four following cases: departure on crusade; knighting of the eldest son; dowry of the eldest daughter; ransom of the overlord if taken prisoner. In return, the seigneur swore to protect the commune and respect its rights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the belfries now in existence are successors to wooden constructions, often destroyed by fire and known only through archives, which give no descriptions. The multi-purpose belfry soon came to be built of stone to prevent the risk of future fires. Its imposing volume formed either an isolated feature or a central or lateral element of the market halls, themselves often rebuilt in stone at an early date.&lt;/p&gt;</historical_description><http_url>http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/943</http_url><id_number>943</id_number><image_url>http://whc.unesco.org/uploads/sites/site_943.jpg</image_url><iso_code>fr,be</iso_code><justification></justification><latitude>50.1744400000</latitude><location></location><longitude>3.2313900000</longitude><long_description>&lt;p&gt;Belfries are outstanding representatives of civic and public architecture in Europe. Through the variety of their 'functional' forms and the changes they have undergone they have been a vital aspect of civic architecture in Europe since the 13th century. They are unique constructions reflecting the development of civil authority that marked the history of Flanders (in its historical sense) from the Middle Ages onwards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Referring originally to mobile wooden towers used in siege warfare, the term was later applied to the wooden watchtowers mounted on the palisades surrounding the portus or pre-urban centres. It was to be applied in particular to those housing bells or standing next to the bell tower. Palisades, bells and the right to possess bells are all closely associated with the development of urban life. The 31 belfries in Flanders and Wallonia and the 23 in north-eastern France, invariably found in an urban setting, are imposing bell towers of medieval origin, generally attached to the town hall and occasionally to a church. In addition to their outstanding artistic value, the belfries are potent symbols of the transition from feudalism to the mercantile urban society that played a vital role in the development of late medieval Europe. The belfries are both civic buildings and symbols, and highly significant tokens of the achievement of civil liberties acquired through the dissolution the abbeys that had remained sovereign since the high Middle Ages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;The early belfries of the 13th and early 14th centuries are strongly reminiscent of the seignieurial keep, from which they take their massive square form, elevations showing sparing use of openings, and rising storeys built on or designed for vaulting. The main shaft is topped by a wall walk and parapet running between bartizans: the central spire features a slate campanile roof and variations on a number of forms. The finials of the corner and central turrets are decorated with animals or symbolic characters protecting the commune. The 13th-century belfry of Ieper (Ypres) is a fine example of this type, although it forms part of the market hall complex later to include the town hall, construction of which continued down to the 17th century.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the examples concerned cover the periods of the 14th-15th and 16th-17th centuries, thereby offering an illustration of the transition in style from Norman Gothic to later Gothic, which then mingles with Renaissance and Baroque forms. In the 14th and 15th centuries, the belfries abandoned the model of the keep in favour of finer, taller towers, such as those of Dendermonde, Lier and Aalst. The subsequent addition to the top of the shaft of a narrower, different shape to serve as the base for the campanile would give the desired monumental effect, and the roof itself would take on more bulbous, sometimes extended lines, as in the case of Veurne (17th century).&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;When the market halls and belfries grew too small to function as a meeting-place for the aldermen, a new type of building was required, the H&amp;ocirc;tel de Ville (town hall), clearly designed in accordance with the administrative organization and, from the 15th and 16th centuries onwards, assuming an obvious representative role achieved by incorporating the symbolic belfry, as in the examples of Brussels and Oudenaarde.&lt;/p&gt;&#xd;
&lt;p&gt;Their construction often took place in several stages, but they have always been maintained in good overall order. Some, damaged by war, have been rebuilt, generally in identical form. All are listed as historic monuments, either in isolation or as part of an edifice, a square, or an urban site.&lt;/p&gt;</long_description><region>Europe and North America</region><revision_extension>Bis</revision_extension><secondary_dates>2005</secondary_dates><short_description>&lt;p&gt;Twenty-three belfries in the north of France and the belfry of Gembloux in Belgium were inscribed as a group, an extension to the 32 Belgian belfries inscribed in 1999 as Belfries of Flanders and Wallonia. Built between the 11th and 17th centuries, they showcase the Roman, Gothic, Renaissance and Baroque styles of architecture. They are highly significant tokens of the winning of civil liberties. While Italian, German and English towns mainly opted to build town halls, in part of north-western Europe, greater emphasis was placed on building belfries. Compared with the keep (symbol of the seigneurs) and the bell-tower (symbol of the Church), the belfry, the third tower in the urban landscape, symbolizes the power of the aldermen. Over the centuries, they came to represent the influence and wealth of the towns.&lt;/p&gt;</short_description><site>Belfries of Belgium and France</site><states>France,Belgium</states><transboundary>1</transboundary><unique_number>1100</unique_number></row></query>